# **STAN OSIPENKO**

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Github</u> <u>stan.xyz</u> me@stan.xyz

#### **PROFILE**

I'm passionate about software engineering & game programming. I am also very enthusiastic about opening up access to education, working previously at non-profit education companies teaching Python, Scratch, Javascript, & HTML. I've been making software for more than 4 years in Python, Node.js, & Bash. I've also made over 50 games using C, C++, JS, & Lua.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Codelab / Imperial College London**

Sep 2018 - Sep 2020

<u>Codelab</u> is a project of the department of computing providing opportunities to less fortunate kids (aged 6-17) to learn computing & programming skills. Using the <u>TuringLab</u> platform, I initially started as a teaching assistant, but over the course of 2019 I took on more organisation & management roles, becoming a teacher in October 2019.

Private Tutor Sep 2019 - Sep 2020

During weekly sessions, we often did <u>LeetCode</u>, <u>CodinGame</u>, & various other problems I came up with in my spare time. I also helped a student with their Computing GCSE. <u>Reference</u> from a parent of one of the students.

Chocolate Minds Mar 2020 - Oct 2020

<u>Chocolate Minds</u> is a non-profit education company teaching Python, HTML, & Scratch. While teaching, I designed Python courses. Being one of the first teachers there meant I was able to design & deliver free programming classes for children of key workers in response to the coronavirus pandemic.

Flashpoint VC Jun 2020 - Aug 2020

<u>Flashpoint VC</u> is a technology investment firm focused on investing in teams primarily from central & eastern Europe. During my internship, I improved my research & analytical skills of Series B / C companies and learned more about venture capital as a whole.

# **EDUCATION**

Latymer Upper School, London UK - Secondary / High School: Academic Mentor: Mandarin & Computing. Studying A-levels: Maths, Further Maths, Physics, Computing.

Funtech PureCoder 1-3 Course (3 years): C#, Java, Web Dev, Stacks, Big O Notation, MySQL, JQuery.

CS50 Harvard: Harvard's 12-week introductory computer science course. Certificate.

### **PROJECTS**

A\*: A\* pathfinding algorithm in Python.

**Traffic Simulator:** Simplified traffic simulation in Lua.

Net-Pong: Online pong with custom networking in C++.

More at stan.xyz/projects or Github.

#### **OTHER**

- Russian: Fluent + GCSE A\*. Mandarin: Conversant, HSK 3.
- Winner of debating competition (DebateMate competition, 300+ people).
- **UKMT Maths Challenge:** 3x Gold 2x Kangaroo.
- Clarinet: Grade 8 (Highest), Grade 5 Jazz (Highest).
- Kick Boxing & Jiu-Jitsu.